<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         role="homepage"
         version="5.2">
<title>XML Catalogs</title>

<para>This is the home/a launching page for the
<link xlink:href="catalogs-1.1.html">XML Catalogs</link>
specification. XML Catalogs were developed to address an
interoperability requirement:</para>

<blockquote role="abstract">
<para>The requirement that all external identifiers in XML documents must
provide a system identifier has unquestionably been of tremendous
short-term benefit to the XML community. It has allowed a whole
generation of tools to be developed without the added complexity of
explicit entity management.</para>

<para>However, the interoperability of XML documents has been impeded in
several ways by the lack of entity management facilities:</para>

<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>External identifiers may require resources that are not always
available. For example, a system identifier that points to a resource
on another machine may be inaccessible if a network connection is not
available.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>External identifiers may require protocols that are not accessible to
all of the vendors' tools on a single computer system. An external
identifier that is addressed with the ftp: protocol, for example, is
not accessible to a tool that does not support that protocol.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>It is often convenient to access resources using system identifiers
that point to local resources. Exchanging documents that refer to
local resources with other systems is problematic at best and
impossible at worst.
</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>

<para>The problems involved with sharing documents, or packages of
documents, across multiple systems are large and complex. While there
are many important issues involved and a complete solution is beyond
the current scope, the OASIS membership agrees upon the enclosed set
of conventions to address a useful subset of the complete problem. To
address these issues, this OASIS Standard defines an entity catalog
that maps both external identifiers and arbitrary URI references to
URI references.</para>
</blockquote>

<para>XML Catalogs were developed at
<link xlink:href="http://www.oasis-open.org/">OASIS</link> by the
<link xlink:href="http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/tc_home.php?wg_abbrev=entity">OASIS
Entity Resolution Technical Committee</link>. They are based on earlier work on
SGML Catalogs.</para>

<para>This site exists in part because OASIS have disbanded the comments
mailing list and the useful, stand-alone versions of the schemas now
return 404.</para>

<section xml:id="schemas">
<title>The Catalog Schemas</title>

<para>The OASIS Standard, version 1.1 schemas are available here:</para>

<orderedlist>
<listitem><para><link xlink:href="schema/1.1/catalog.xsd">http://xmlcatalogs.org/schema/1.1/catalog.xsd</link>
(W3C XML Schema)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link xlink:href="schema/1.1/catalog.rng">http://xmlcatalogs.org/schema/1.1/catalog.rng</link>
(RELAX NG)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link xlink:href="schema/1.1/catalog.rnc">http://xmlcatalogs.org/schema/1.1/catalog.rnc</link>
(RELAX NG Compact Syntax)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link xlink:href="schema/1.1/catalog.dtd">http://xmlcatalogs.org/schema/1.1/catalog.dtd</link>
(XML DTD)</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>

<para><emphasis>Non-normative</emphasis>, experimental version 1.2 schemas are availble here:</para>

<orderedlist>
<listitem><para><link xlink:href="schema/1.2beta/catalog.xsd">http://xmlcatalogs.org/schema/1.2beta/catalog.xsd</link>
(W3C XML Schema)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link xlink:href="schema/1.2beta/catalog.rng">http://xmlcatalogs.org/schema/1.2beta/catalog.rng</link>
(RELAX NG)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link xlink:href="schema/1.2beta/catalog.rnc">http://xmlcatalogs.org/schema/1.2beta/catalog.rnc</link>
(RELAX NG Compact Syntax)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link xlink:href="schema/1.2beta/catalog.dtd">http://xmlcatalogs.org/schema/1.2beta/catalog.dtd</link>
(XML DTD)</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>

<para>The 1.2beta schemas are identical to the standard 1.1 schemas with one small exception:
a bug in the definition of <code>pubIdChars</code> simple type in the W3C XML Schema has
been corrected. In the standard 1.1 schemas, <code>pubIdChars</code> incorrectly excludes
the space character.</para>
</section>

<section xml:id="implementations">
<title>Implementations</title>

<para>Many XML products come with catalog support built in. If you want to add it to your
applications, these libraries may help:</para>

<orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para><link xlink:href="https://github.com/ndw/xmlresolver">XML Resolver</link> is a
Java implementation.
</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><link xlink:href="https://github.com/ndw/xmlresolvercs">XML Resolver CS</link> is a
C# implementation.
</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><link xlink:href="http://xml.apache.org/commons/">XML Commons</link> at
<link xlink:href="http://www.apache.org/">Apache</link> is a much older Java
implementation.</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>
</article>
